# Shubham Gulati

Senior Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 7 Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech

Waterloo, ON • linkedin.com/in/iamshgulati • shubhamgulati.com

#### **PROFILE**

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS. His core competencies include cloud-native web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- Lead a team of junior developers that enhanced the accuracy of a reporting application by 30%.
- Streamlined development lifecycle by enforcing coding best practices and improved reliability of the system.
- Reduced the risk of security incidents by designing a framework to fetch configuration secrets from HashiCorp Vault.

#### **Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting**

India - 2019-2022

- Developed the client's support portal which is a one stop shop for all the support related needs for business users.
- Reduced technical debt for a major client project by developing a common foundation for microservice modules.
- Improved the performance of mission-critical features by 25% by optimizing code and database queries.

#### Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2018-2019

- Developed client's HR Portal which was a regulated product with highly sensitive data and numerical operations.
- Reduced the operational costs of the portal by 20% by re-writing Coldfusion application using Java & Spring Boot.
- Improved the efficiency and security of the modules by 80% by re-architecting backend services for the cloud.

#### Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

India - 2016-2018

- Developed a framework to manage the state of system which reduced the maintenance downtime by 95%.
- Migrated SOAP web services to REST endpoints using modern Spring Boot-based microservices.

#### **EDUCATION**

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College	Waterloo, ON
Postgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic	Saskatoon, SK
Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology	India
Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology	India

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	Pursuing
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

#### **SKILLS**

Backend	- Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, JPA, Hibernate, REST, GraphQL, Git, SQL, OpenAPI, Swagger
Cloud/Infra	- AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM), GCP, GitHub Actions, Docker, Jenkins
Frontend	<ul> <li>SSG, SSR, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Next.js, Astro.js</li> </ul>

August 23, 2024 Shubham Gulati • Résumé 1 of 2

### **AWARDS**

Conestoga	- High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security.	2024
Conestoga	- Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Saskpoly	- Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain.	2023
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project.</li> </ul>	2022
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project.</li> </ul>	2020
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project.</li> </ul>	2019
Deloitte	- Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project.	2019
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live.</li> </ul>	2019
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development.</li> </ul>	2018
CGI	<ul> <li>Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project.</li> </ul>	2017

## **PROJECTS**

Blog	-	Self-taught React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Next.js, and Astro.js to build a blog with a simple design.
<b>OSCAR</b>	_	Secured Maven build supply chain for OSCAR, an open-source Canadian Healthcare EMR system.
<b>Emoverse</b>	-	Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI-CD pipeline.
<b>SmartDeg</b>	ree -	Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain.
<u>DevMyMa</u>	<u>cX</u> –	Self-taught shell scripting to automate user and developer environment setup on a fresh macOS install.
<u>DevMyLin</u>	<u>uX</u> –	Self-taught shell scripting to automate Arch Linux OS and environment setup with minimal user interaction.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Research Paper

- + An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- + Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723